in this video we're going to take a
closer look at the idea of relations
which are something that we've
previously seen for now you'll recall
that a relation is to let it involve two
different set you had a set a and you
had a set B and I'm put a bunch of
elements inside of a and I put a bunch
of elements inside of B then you could
visualize sort of an arrow diagram for a
relation which is connections from the
set a to the set B so for example I can
have these connections where the the a
one is going to go down to the B 2 and
the a five is goes to the B 2 and the a
3 is going to be 1 and the B 4 and so on
and then you would be able to sometimes
say that a relation was a function if
additionally it had the property of
passing the vertical line test and that
everything in the domain went somewhere
we've previously discussed that and then
our formal definition for what a
relation was is going to be the
following
it is a set of the Cartesian product
that is I look at all pairs something in
a something in B that's what the
Cartesian project pairs we choose a
first thing in a and a second thing in B
and then we say that some pair like say
how about a 1 B 2 that is an element of
your relation if when you look at this
arrow diagram a 1 really is related to B
2 and then the nomenclature we had is
we're going to say that an element in R
is written as a relates to be precisely
lame little a comma little B was an
element of your Cartesian product or
there was an arrow up here in your arrow
diagram now if I have a relation I can
also define something referred to as the
inverse relation and the idea of an
inverse relation is it's exactly doing
what the relation from A to B did but it
flips it around so for example let me
put up my relation R that I saw before
for the inverse relation we're going to
try to take the a and the B and we're
going to try to swap them so I
put them up I'm not going to fill in the
arrow just for the moment but for the in
Reverse relation first of all the the
starting set your domain if you will is
the be your codomain is the age so we
flip that order and then if I think
about how I should be connecting these
well for instance if I go over here the
B 1 is connected down to the a3 the the
B 2 is connected up to the a1 and the a5
and so on so I can fill in my line like
this where these connections are exactly
this picture but it's the mirror image
of that picture